carnegieendowment.org 2012-10-28

# About - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace

## Disclaimer

The Carnegie Endowment does not take institutional positions on public policy issues; the views represented on this website are the author’s own and do not necessarily reflect the views of the Endowment, its staff, or its trustees. 

## Privacy Policy

This site is owned and operated by The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace. Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us. 

Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we feel you should fully understand our policy and the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it, all of which comply with common web standards.

The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace gathers two types of information about users:

* Information that users provide through optional, voluntary submissions. These are voluntary submissions to receive our electronic newsletters, to participate in our forums, to email a friend, and from participation in surveys.

* Information The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace gathers through aggregated tracking information derived mainly by tallying page views throughout our sites. This information allows us to better tailor our content to readers' needs and to help our funders better understand the demographics of our audience. Under no circumstances does The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace divulge any information about an individual user to a third party. 

The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace Gathers User Information In The Following Processes:

_Optional Voluntary Information_

We offer the following free services, which require some type of voluntary submission of personal information by users:

  1. Email Policy 

Our email outreach is permission based. If you received a mailing from us, our records indicate that (a) you have expressly shared this address for the purpose of receiving information in the future ("opt-in"), or (b) you have registered or otherwise have an existing relationship with us. We respect your time and attention by controlling the frequency of our mailings.

We may periodically send promotional email about new publication releases or events which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided. 

If you believe you have received unwanted, unsolicited email sent via this system or purporting to be sent via this system, please forward a copy of that email with your comments to [info@ceip.org](mailto:info@ceip.org) for review. 

Each email sent contains an easy way for you to cease receiving email from us. If you wish to do this, simply click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the any email, or contact [info@ceip.org](mailto:info@ceip.org).

  2. Forums policy 

Users of the site's forums may be required to include an email address. This email address may be used by staff of The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace to contact the commenter.

  3. "E-mail this to a friend" policy 

Our site users can choose to electronically forward a page to someone else by clicking "e-mail this to a friend". The user must provide their email address, as well as that of the recipient. This information is used only in the case of transmission errors and, of course, to let the recipient know who sent the email. The information is not used for any other purpose.

  4. Surveys   

The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace may occasionally conduct user surveys to better target our content to our audience. We sometimes share the aggregated demographic information in these surveys with our funders. We never share any of this information about specific individuals with any third party.

_Children_

Consistent with the Federal Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent.

_Usage tracking_

The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace tracks user traffic patterns throughout all of our sites. However, we do not correlate this information with data about individual users. The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace does break down overall usage statistics according to a user's domain name, browser type, and MIME type by reading this information from the browser string (information contained in every user's browser).

The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace sometimes tracks and catalogs the search terms that users enter in our Search function, but this tracking is never associated with individual users. We use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you.

_Cookies_

We may place a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain Personal Information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie cannot read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace uses cookies to track user traffic patterns (as described above). 

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. If you've set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site. However, you do need cookies to participate actively in surveys.

_Web Beacons_

When we send you emails, we may include a web beacon to allow us to determine the number of people who open our emails. When you click on a link in an email, we may record this individual response to allow us to customize our offerings to you. Web beacons collect only limited information, such as a cookie identifier, time and date of a page being viewed, and a description of the page on which the Web Beacon resides (the URL). Web Beacons can be refused when delivered via email. If you do not wish to receive Web Beacons via email, you will need to disable HTML images or refuse HTML (select Text only) emails via your email software.

_Third-Party Service Providers_

We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. This includes fulfilling book orders, delivering packages, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes. 

Order processing requires that we provide credit card numbers to the appropriate credit card company. The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace does not retain any credit card information associated with purchases made through www.carnegieendowment.org.

###### USE OF INFORMATION  

The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience in our network of sites, whether to provide interactive or personalized elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users.

As stated above, we use information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out electronic newsletters and to enable users to participate in surveys and forums. We send out newsletters to subscribers on a regular schedule (depending on the newsletter), and occasionally send out special editions, event-related emails, and announcements when we think subscribers might be particularly interested in something we are doing. The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace never shares mailing lists with any third parties.

When we use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas, we do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered in Search function as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don't track which terms a particular user enters.

###### SHARING OF THE INFORMATION  

The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace uses the above-described information to tailor our content to suit your needs and help our funders better understand our audience's demographics. We will not share information about individual users with any third party, except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public.

###### SECURITY  

The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace operates secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our customers.

###### OPT-OUT POLICY  

We give users options wherever necessary and practical. Such choices include:

  * Opting not to register to receive our electronic newsletters.
  * Opting not to participate in certain interactive areas, which completely alleviates the need to gather any personally identifiable information from our users

###### YOUR CONSENT  

By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.
